<tips>
  <tip id="1">
    <item><![CDATA[Quoll Writer has a Patreon page.  If you want to help speed up development why not consider donating?  <a href="https://www.patreon.com/quollwriter?ty=h">Click here to view the Patreon page</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="2">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Did you know you can keep track of how much of a {chapter} you have edited?  Just right click at any point in the chapter and select <b>[Chapter] Edit</b> then [edit-point] <b>Set Edit Point</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="3">
    <item><![CDATA[Don't like what things are called?  <a href="action:editobjectnames">Click here to change them.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="4">
    <item><![CDATA[There is an option to compress the right click menu you see when editing a {chapter}. <a href="action:options.editing">Click here to view options.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="5">
    <item><![CDATA[Don't like the position of the tabs?  Change it in the options.  <a href="action:options.look">Click here to view options.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="6">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to see where you are writing?  Enable writing line highlighting in the text properties.  <a href="action:textproperties">Click here to view the text properties now.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="7">
    <item condition="!options"><![CDATA[Want to change something?  <a href="action:options">Check out the options, there might be a setting for it.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="8">
    <item><![CDATA[Changing the setting of an option will take effect straight away, no need to save.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="9">
    <item condition="!landingviewer"><![CDATA[Want to work in full screen mode?  <a href="action:fullscreen">Click to enter full screen mode now.</a><br />You can also press F5 or use the [fullscreen,fullscreen] button on the toolbar to enter full screen mode.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="10">
    <item><![CDATA[Can't remember what the awesome was added in this release?  <a href="action:whatsnew">Click to see what's new.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="11">
    <item><![CDATA[Got writer's block?  <a href="action:warmup">Why not try a warm-up exercise?</a> To do a warm-up at any time select [warmups]<b>Do a Warm-up Exercise</b> from the project menu.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="12">
    <item condition="!ideaboard,projectviewer"><![CDATA[Want to record your ideas?  <a href="action:ideaboard">Click to open the Idea Board.</a><br />You can open the idea board at any time by selecting [idea]<b>Idea Board</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="13">
    <item><![CDATA[Have you seen the user guide?  <a href="help:index.html">Click to view the guide.</a> You can access the online help at any time from the project menu, then select [help]<b>Help</b> then [help]<b>View the User Guide</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>
  <tip id="14">
    <item id="1" condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to know how many words you've written?  <a href="action:wordcounts">Click to see the word counts now.</a><br />You can also use <b>Ctrl+W</b> or the [wordcount] button from the toolbar to see how many words you've written.]]></item>
    <item id="2" condition="!chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to know how many words you've written?  Press <b>Ctrl+W</b> when editing a chapter or use the [wordcount] button from the toolbar to see how many words you've written.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="15">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to know see how many words you've written over time? <a href="action:wordcounthistory">Click to see the word count history now.</a><br />Press <b>Ctrl+W</b> or use the [wordcount] button from the toolbar then [wordcount]<b>View Detail</b> to view the history.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="16">
    <item><![CDATA[Want to manage the words in your personal dictionary?  <a href="action:dictionarymanager">Click to manage your personal dictionary now.</a><br />The dictionary can be accessed from the project menu then select [edit-properties]<b>Project Options</b> and the <b>Chapter</b> tab.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="17">
    <item condition="chaptertab,spellcheckon"><![CDATA[Sick of those little red lines?  <a href="action:spellcheckoff">Click to turn the spellchecker off.</a><br />Press <b>Ctrl+L</b> when editing a chapter or use the [spellchecker] button on the toolbar to turn the spellchecker on or off.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="18">
    <item><![CDATA[Want to keep track of your achievements?  <a href="action:achievements">Click to check your achievements now.</a><br />You can track your progress at any time by selecting [achievement]<b>Achievements</b> from the project menu.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="19">
    <item><![CDATA[Like to use the keyboard rather than the mouse?  <a href="help:main-window/keyboard-shortcuts">Click to view the shortcuts.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="20">
    <item><![CDATA[You can import Microsoft Word files into your project. <a href="action:import">Click to import a file.</a><br />You can also select [project-import]<b>Import File</b> from the project menu to import.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="21">
    <item condition="projectviewer"><![CDATA[You can export your project to a number of different file formats?  <a href="action:export">Click to export your project.</a><br />You can also select [project-export]<b>Export Project</b> from the project menu to export.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="22">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to improve your writing and find problems with the text?   <a href="action:problemfinder">Click to view the problem finder.</a><br />The problem finder can be accessed from the [tools] tools menu on the toolbar then selecting [eye]<b>Problem Finder</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="23">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[You can use the problem finder in full screen mode.  <a href="action:fullscreen,problemfinder">Click to view the problem finder in full screen mode now.</a><br />Full screen mode can be accessed from the toolbar by selecting [fullscreen] or pressing <b>F5</b>. The problem finder can be accessed from the [tools] tools menu on the toolbar then selecting [eye]<b>Find Problems</b> or using the shortcut <b>Ctrl+Shift+P</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="24">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to check how readable your prose is?  <a href="action:wordcounts">Click to view the check the readability now.</a><br />You can also check the readability by opening the word counts via <b>Ctrl+W</b> or use the [wordcount] button on the toolbar.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="25">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Don't like the font or font size?  <a href="action:textproperties">Click to change the text properties.</a><br />The text properties can be accessed from the [tools] menu on the toolbar then select [edit-properties]<b>Edit Text Properties</b>.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="26">
    <item id="1" condition="!chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to find a synonym?  Highlight a word while editing a chapter and right click.]]></item>
    <item id="2" condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Want to find a synonym?  Highlight a word and right click.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="27">
    <item condition="chaptertab"><![CDATA[Missing the sound of a typewriter?  <a href="action:enabletypewritersound">Click to try out the typewriter sound.</a><br />You can turn the sound on or off (and change it) in the <b>How things look and sound</b> section of the <a href="action:options.look">options</a>.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="28">
    <item><![CDATA[Warm-ups can be converted into projects.  <a href="action:warmup">Click to do a warm-up now.</a><br />You can do a warm-up at any time, just select [warmups]<b>Do a Warm-up Exercise</b> from the project menu.]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="29">
    <item><![CDATA[In full screen mode you can change the size of the writing area and how transparent the background is?  Just move your cursor to the top of the screen to see the options.]]></item>
  </tip>

  <tip id="30">
    <item condition="!landingviewer"><![CDATA[Did you know that in full screen mode you can change the color of the text and the background of the writing area? <a href="action:fullscreen">Click to enter full screen mode now.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="31">
    <item condition="!landingviewer"><![CDATA[Did you know that in full screen mode you can set an image for the background?  <a href="action:fullscreen">Click to enter full screen mode now.</a>]]></item>
  </tip>
  
  <tip id="32">
    <item condition="!landingviewer"><![CDATA[Looking to find where a word or term is mentioned?  <a href="action:find">Click to open the find.</a><br />You can open the find with <b>Ctrl+F</b> or select [find]<b>Find</b> from the project menu at any time.]]></item>
  </tip>
</tips>